Guide to the Pamela Bolen Collection on Washington Square United Methodist Church MC.181
New York University Archives
Pamela Bolen Collection on Washington Square United Methodist Church
1972-1980
New York University Archives
Bolen, Pamela
MC.181
0.5 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box.
Pamela Bolen served on various boards and committees of the Washington Square United Methodist Church (WSUMC) in the 1970s. The collection contains materials Bolen created and gathered while at WSUMC. The collection consists of meeting minutes, reports, notebooks, printed ephemera, correspondence, publications, sheet music, by-laws, renovation proposals, and a research paper. Materials date from 1972 to 1980.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Pamela Bolen in 2005. The accession number associated with this collection is 05.008.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Biographical Note
Pamela Bolen received a BA in musicology from the University of California, Riverside, and a MA in religion from New York University. Bolen has worked at NYU in a number of positions, including Director of Career Planning and Placement (1988-1990), Director of Student Programming and Facilities (1990-2003), Executive Director of the Kimmel Center (2003-2011), and Consultant for Event and Conference Space Management (2011-2018).
Bolen served on boards and committees of the Washington Square United Methodist Church (WSUMC) for most of the 1970s. WSUMC was known as the Peace Church due to its anti-Vietnam activism. The church was also known for welcoming gays and lesbians as the church was the site for the Harvey Milk School of Lesbian and Gay Youth. Bolen served on the WSUMC Administrative Board, Staff/Parish Relations Committee, and was chairperson of the Renovations Committee.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains materials Bolen created and gathered while serving on boards and committees of the Washington Square United Methodist Church (WSUMC). Collection materials appear to be organized by Bolen as subject files relating to WSUMC events, programs, meetings, and projects. These record broadly address the church's history, renovation plans, and work with the gay and lesbian community. The collection consists of meeting minutes, reports, notebooks, newsletters, flyers, pamphlets, correspondence, publications, sheet music, press releases, by-laws, renovation proposals, and a research paper. Materials date from 1972 to 1980.
Methodist church.; Church work with gays.; Methodist church buildings.; Bolen, Pamela; Washington Square United Methodist Church
- Architectural History of the Washington Square United Methodist Church research paper by Anthony W. Robins, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Arts, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Preservation plan, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Archival project, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Board of Trustees meetings, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Newsletters, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Homosexuality, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Publications, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Program, 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Renovations, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Reports, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Staff/Parish Relations Committee, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)